CÉLINE PICAUT

Madrid, Spain

(+34) 671448691 | cpicaut.ieu2017@student.ie.edu

Eligible to sign internship agreement via IE University

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Great aptitude to embrace different cultures and adapt to changes. Lived in different countries such as Mexico, France, Spain, Romania, India, Poland and Switzerland. Ability with languages, four spoken fluently, currently learning the fifth one. Motivated with experience in the field of international security. Available from May 2022.

EDUCATION

IE UNIVERSITY Madrid, Spain **Expected: May 2022**

Dual Bachelor in Business Administration and International Relations

GPA: 8.76/10.00; Awarded Academic Excellence Scholarship

Honors: International Unplugged I, II and III; Political Theory; Chinese I, II and III; Comparative Politics

SCIENCES PO PARIS Paris, France

Academic Exchange August 2021- December 2021

Courses: Sexual Violence in Armed Conflicts; France and the United States in the Middle East; The European Union and the Western Balkans; National Security Policy of China; Trade and International Finance

BROWN UNIVERSITY

Course on Social Innovation

Grade: A

THE FRENCH SCHOOL OF NEW DELHI

French Baccalaureate (BAC)

Grade: 18/20; Major of Promotion. Economic and Social section: Specialization in Mathematics

July 2019

September 2015 - July 2017

Providence, United States

New Delhi. India

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KIMPA - IMPACT FAMILY OFFICE

Madrid, Spain January 2022- June 2022

Marketing Officer

Created content such as blog articles, landing pages, social media posts and customer cases on the topics of impact finance and sustainable development

- Analyzed and followed-up the weekly impact of the editorial calendar
- Preformed Inbound Marketing and designed the website

ORGANIZATION OF AMERICAN STATES - INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATION

Washington DC, United States

June 2021 - August 2021

Cybersecurity Intern at the Inter-American Committee Against Terrorism

- Supported Policy Development, including in the meeting of the Working Group on Confidence Building Measures in Cyberspace, the organization of courses related to cyber-diplomacy and National Cybersecurity Strategies
- Developed communication materials including awareness campaigns, reports, and whitepapers
- Assisted CSIRTAmericas and Cybersecurity Incident Response Teams

HARVARD KENNEDY SCHOOL SPAIN ALUMNI - NGO

Policy and Communications Intern

Madrid, Spain December 2020 - October 2021

Elaborated a communications strategy to position and promote the association Drafted policy memos to advise the Spanish Government on public policies and improve the quality of public service

UNITED NATIONS OFFICE AT GENEVA - INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATION

Social Media and Outreach Intern

Geneva, Switzerland June 2020 - August 2020

- Created, amplified and scheduled content for the 4 UNOG social media pages (Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, Instagram)
- Monitored media to write 2 reports per day
- Summarized 2 press briefings per week to be published on the United Nations website
- Did 1 report per month using excel, portraying the monthly performance of the accounts
- Covered events happening at the Palais des Nations such as the Human Rights Council or the Conference on Disarmament

MUJERES POR ÁFRICA - NGO

Assistant of the Presidential Cabinet

Wrote and translated over 50 administrative documents in three languages: English, French and Spanish

Madrid, Spain June 2018 - July 2018

- Organized events such as "El Faro de Nador", attended by hundreds of people including the Queen of Spain and various political figures
- Gathered information from several sources and analyzed data obtained to write 5 reports on women's conditions over past 10 years

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

- Awards:
 - Received First Price of IEU Agora Festival rewarding public speaking (Madrid, Spain. April 2019)
 - Awarded First Prize of IEU Business Plan Challenge after creating a proposal of an app for youth employment (Madrid, Spain. May 2018)
- Volunteer Work:
 - Volunteer for COP 25 helping in matters related to logistics and information, promoting the sustainable development goals and assisting medias (Madrid, Spain. December 2019).
 - Volunteer for Kamalini as English teacher for class of 20 young Indian Girls (New Delhi, India. September 2015 June 2017).
 - Volunteer for Renasterea, organizing events to promote awareness on Women's Health (Bucharest, Romania. October 2013).

- Languages: Spanish (Native), French (Native), English (Fluent), Romanian (Fluent), Chinese (Elementary),
- Computer Skills: Advanced user of MS Office, Adobe photoshop, Adobe Premiere and social media networks
- **Hobbies:** Travelling and Sailing